come on in.
进来吧
i'm not doing any more chemo.
我不要再做化疗了
good plan. you'll be dead in five months.
有想法 五个月后你就升天
we went for a cure. it didn't work.
我们试过治疗了 但没有用
i've thought about this a lot.
我考虑了很多
five more months on this earth is reasonable.
在这地球上再多待五个月也可以了
a year in the hospital in excruciating pain is...
躺在医院里一年 承受巨大痛苦折磨...
not.
就算了吧
with two weeks on, two weeks off of chemo, you'll have way more than a year,
两个星期间隔做化疗 你能活不止一年呢
maybe two or three.
两三年也说不定
house...
House...
i'm sorry.
抱歉
i'm not gonna let you just die.
我不能让你就这么死了
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生  第八季第21集
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生  第八季第21集
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：ID 校对：ID 时间轴：绿
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：王母娘娘眼泪尽情流 FF心疼HW 校对：酒囊饭袋快给拿纸巾来 时间轴：绿
hey. you know, management research shows that the best ideas come from casual contact.
嘿 知道吗 管理研究表示 最好的主意都来自于即兴交谈
so... one set of season tickets.
所以... 这一季的套票
got the seat next to you.
我是你旁边的位子
first game is october 8th.
第一场是10月8日
that's about one month after wilson's expiration date.
是Wilson小命到期的一个月后
this isn't an unstructured collaboration.
这明显是有备而来
you're trying to be the new wilson.
你是想成为新一代的Wilson
i'm trying to show you there are other people who care about you.
我是想告诉你 还有其他人也关心你的
relax.
甭担心
i'm probably not gonna fall apart.
我应该不会垮掉的
step away from the computer. 46-year-old oncologist refuses treatment.
视线离开电脑 46岁的肿瘤专家拒绝治疗
foreman already gave us a case.
Foreman已经给了我们一个病例
wants us to keep things as normal as possible for as long as possible.
希望我们尽可能地保持正常运作
wilson is dying. chase is gone.
Wilson要死 Chase走人
how close to normal do you think we can come?
你觉得咱还能多正常?
19-year-old cheerleader admitted with massive nosebleed and dizziness.
19岁的啦啦队员 因为大量流鼻血和头晕被送进来
wow. cool.
哇噢 好酷诶
i just completely forgot that my best friend is dying.
我彻底忘记我闺蜜要死了呢
wait. that just reminded me. head ct is clean.
- 不对 这下我又想起来了 - 头部扫描没有异常
how can we turn wilson from a terminal idiot into an interminable pain in the ass?
咱们怎么才能让Wilson从一个晚期白痴 变成一个老不死的麻烦呢?
mini stroke could explain our patient's neurosymptoms and his butterfingers.
小中风可以解释病人的神经系统症状 以及手滑
but not his bloody nose.
但无法解释流鼻血的症状
my best friend is trying to kill himself.
我的闺蜜打算自杀
he just wants to die with a little dignity.
他是想有尊严地死去
there's no such thing.
纯属放屁
it's not your choice, house.
这不是你说得算的 House
your only choice here is between acceptance and misery.
你只有接受和痛苦这两条路可以走
it's a midline granuloma. get your patient a pet scan.
是中线肉芽 给病人做PET扫描
no lesions along the optic track? you already covered that.
视神经没有障碍 你已经查过了
maybe we should get someone else to take this case.
或许应该把这个病例交给别人
why? because someone somewhere is dying?
为什么 因为某处的某人要死了?
oh, crap, turn off the mike! it is off.
- 该死 把麦克风关上 - 已经关了啊
not according to his brain.
从他大脑看来并非如此
his temporal lobe is completely lit up.
他的颞叶明显活跃了
auditory portion.
听觉部分
he's hearing something.
他听到了什么
foreman's trying to date me.
Foreman想跟我约会
i assume that's because you called him.
我想是因为你跟他说了什么
no, i-- did you...
没有 我...你是不是...
put something in my coffee?
在我的咖啡里放了什么
you know how you can be there for me five months from now?
你知道 从现在开始你可以怎样陪我五个月吗
don't be dead five months from now.
就是好好活到五个月后
hey, wils--
嘿 Wils...
seriously? just a little picker-downer.
- 真的吗? - 就是用了点镇静剂罢了
i assume this unwanted interruption means you're looking for me to discuss the latest development
我想你们不请自来是因为想找我讨论那个
in the case i don't want to discuss.
我不想讨论的病例的发展情况吧
our patient is hearing voices.
我们的病人听到一些声音
he denies it, but the pet scan says otherwise.
他自己否认 但PET扫描却相反
he's at the right age for the onset of schizophrenia.
他这个年纪正是精神分裂症的开始阶段
yeah. you really need me.
是啊 你们可需要我了
ultrasound his abdomen to check for schizophrenia.
给他腹部做超声波 检查精神分裂
we already ordered a psych evaluation, but drugs could also cause--
我们已经预约了精神鉴定 但是药物还有可能引起...
tox screen was clean. ultrasound his dorm.
- 毒检结果没有问题 - 给他宿舍做超声波
whoa, just...
那个...
you guys can't just come busting in here without a warrant.
你们不能这么擅闯进来
we're not cops. we're your roommate's doctors.
我们不是警察 是你室友的医生
any idea what flavor of drugs would be making your roommate sick?
知道有可能是哪种口味的药 会让你室友生病吗
objection.
反对
entrapment.
执法圈套
i'm pre-law.
我是法学预科
derrick doesn't party.
Derrick不爱玩的
look at this. why would he have a picture of a little boy?
你看 他怎么有一张小男孩的照片?
maybe it's his nephew or something?
也许是他外甥什么的
hidden in his sock drawer?
藏在放袜子的抽屉里?
whoa! creepy.
变态啊
we need to talk to derrick about some medical matters.
我们要和Derrick谈一些医学上的问题
well, she's my girlfriend. she can be here for that.
她是我女朋友 她在这儿没事的
we found this... in your dorm room.
我们在你寝室里 发现了这个
who is that?
这是谁
nobody.
谁也不是
then why was it hidden in a drawer?
那为什么藏在你的袜子抽屉里?
derrick, what's she talking about?
Derrick 她在说什么啊
it's my brother christopher.
是我弟弟Christopher
you never told me you had a brother.
你从没跟我说过你有个弟弟
well, he's been dead almost ten years, so...
他死了快10年了 所以
is that the voice you hear in your head?
你脑袋里听到的就是这个声音吗
and lo, he is risen.
瞧呀 他起身了
so now my hair's gonna fall out next week?
这么说下礼拜我就要开始掉头发了?
no. all i did was temporarily kill you.
不 我只是临时杀了你
how was it? what--i don't-- i wasn't dead.
- 感觉如何 - 什...我...我没有死
i was unconscious. no dreams, no thoughts.
- 我昏迷了 - 没有做梦 大脑一片空白
you experienced nothing.
毫无体验
now, imagine that without the waking up on the couch part.
现在想象一下 只不过除去被叫醒的部分
just nothing times infinity.
永永远远地一片空白
you didn't just prove death is nothing.
你这不是证明死亡就是空白
you proved propofol is.
是证明了麻醉剂异丙酚是如此
you're saying the end is not the end?
你是说 结束不等于结束?
i was expecting "nothing is better than something lousy,"
我还以为你会说"空白总好过受罪"
but not "the angels are waiting for me." i'm not having this conversation.
- 而不是"天使在等着我呢" - 我不想跟你聊
why? 'cause it doesn't make sense?
为什么 因为毫无意义?
because i'm not gonna change your mind, and i don't care.
因为我不能改变你的想法 不过我也不在乎
more importantly, you're not gonna change mine.
更重要的是 你也改变不了我的决定
there is no heaven. there is no hell.
根本没有天堂 也没有地狱
your soul is not gonna float out of your body and join some great unifying energy force.
你的灵魂才不会飘离你的身体 加入什么厉害的合气部队
the fact that you're dying is not gonna change that.
就算快死了 也改变不了这个现实
please...just go.
拜托...走吧
house.
House
i have spent the last 20 years holding the hands of people as they die.
过去这20年里 我都是在别人快死时 握着他们的手
when i watch that transformation...
亲眼目睹这种转变
i'm sorry, i...
抱歉 我...
don't believe that we're just a bag of chemicals.
无法接受我们只是一堆化学元素
so are we gonna talk about the patient or wait for house?
咱们是聊聊病人 还是等House?
viral encephalitis. it's been going on for ten years.
- 病毒性脑炎 - 那得有10年了
i'm gonna go in there and invite him to participate.
我要过去邀请他加入我们
i think he'd welcome the distraction.
我想他会需要找点事来分心的
come with me?
跟我一起?
why?
为什么
when was the last time house listened to anything we said about anything personal?
上一次House有听我们讲任何私人问题时 是什么时候?
maybe you'll feel better,
或许你心里是会好受一点
but sometimes the truth is there's nothing anyone can do.
可有时真相就是 任何人都无能为力
temporal lobe epilepsy.
颞叶癫痫
causes voices, dizziness. trauma from seizure would explain the nose bleed.
引起幻听 头晕 中风创伤可以解释流鼻血
you know about all of my siblings and cousins and aunts and uncles and--
我所有兄弟姐妹 表亲 叔叔阿姨 你都知道
you're overreacting.
你不必大惊小怪
because you don't trust me enough to tell me-- sorry.
- 因为你不信任我 所以不告诉我 - 抱歉
it's time to go down for your test.
该去做检查了
if you wanna wait here, it'll only take about an hour.
如果你想在这儿等的话 只要大概一个小时
no. she's leaving.
不 她要走了
derrick, come on. i mean, we should at least talk.
Derrick 拜托 我们好歹谈谈吧
no i'd rather you just leave.
你还是走吧
and you don't need to come back.
不用再回来了
time. any odd tastes or smells?
时间到 有任何奇怪的味觉和嗅觉吗
nope. feel fine.
没 感觉良好
things look fine on my end too.
我那边看起来也挺正常的
so...
那么..
you won't admit to your doctors that you're hearing your brother's voice,
你不愿意跟医生承认有听到你弟弟的声音
which is dangerous.
这是很危险的
and now you lost your girlfriend over it, which is stupid.
现在你因为这件事跟女朋友闹翻 真是太傻了
i assume there's more to the story?
我想这其中另有隐情?
that's how i was raised. short story.
- 我从小到大都是这样 - 够简洁
yeah.
是啊
my boss is losing his best friend to cancer.
我上司最好的朋友得了癌症
and instead of talking about the pain,
他不肯说出他的痛苦
he's pretending there is no pain because everything can be fixed.
假装轻松 因为一切都有挽回的余地
my father tried to deal with it.
我爸爸试着去面对
ironic that he'd drink himself into oblivion
讽刺的是 他把自己灌到不省人事
after my brother was killed by a drunk driver.
而我弟弟就是被一个酒驾司机撞死的
do you need a tissue?
要给你拿纸巾吗
after dad left, my mom moved us away.
爸爸离开后 妈妈带着我们搬家
she got rid of all the pictures of christopher and never mentioned him again.
她把所有Christopher的照片都扔了 再也不提起他
it was like he never existed.
就像他根本不曾存在
and that worked for us.
我们也都欣然接受了
and yet, you kept one.
但是你却留着一张
uh, my right eye...
我的右眼
i was seeing spots, but now i can't see at all.
我之前看到有斑点 可是现在根本看不到了
is that from the test? no. this is something else.
- 是检查造成的吗 - 不是 是别的问题?
aah! that hurts.
好痛
sorry.
抱歉
how many fingers? two. fuzzy ones, but two.
- 几根手指 - 两根 虽然不清楚 但是两根
there's a clot in the artery behind your eye.
你眼睛后面的动脉里有血栓
i just broke it up. is that bad?
- 被我揉散了 - 严重吗
don't know, because i don't know why it happened.
不知道 因为我不知道怎么会这样
hey. saved us a table. there are no tables.
- 嘿 给咱找张桌子 - 根本没桌子了
i recently hacked into your old files.
我黑进了你以前的档案
found a six-year-old boy with bilateral retinoblastoma.
发现了一个双眼视网膜母细胞瘤的6岁孩子
doctors wanted to take his eyes out before the cancer spread to his brain,
医生想在癌细胞扩散到脑部前摘除他的眼球
and you fought them.
而你却反对
advocated for a new photon beam radiation.
主张一种新的质子束放疗
saved the kid's vision. probably saved his life.
救了这孩子的眼睛 也救了他的命
that was my first case at ppth. mikey kimble.
这是我在PPTH的第一个病例 Mikey kimble
it's michael now.
现在叫Michael了
oh, yeah. this is our table.
没错 这就是咱的桌子
i...
我...
how are you? i'm doing great.
- 你好吗 - 很好
i'm graduating next month.
下个月就要毕业了
already? little mikey?
这么快? 小Mikey
and i got accepted to princeton.
我被普林斯顿录取了
and i'm planning on going to med school.
我想去念医学院
he's going to be a doctor instead of being dead.
他要成为医生 而不是当死人
dr. house told me all about your situation.
House医生跟我说了你的情况
that's why i came.
我就是为此而来的
there's just so much good that you can do, even in a small amount of time.
你能做的好事太多太多了 即便只是在很短的时间内
i wonder...
我在想...
is there anybody else here who's alive today because of dr. james wilson?
今天在场的还有没有谁活到现在 都是因为James wilson医生?
gastric adenocarcinoma. 15 years in remission.
胃腺癌  已经缓解15年了
six grandchildren that i never would have met.
有六个本来我没有希望见到的孙子
thank you, dr. wilson.
谢谢你 Wilson医生
squamous cell lung cancer. 12 years in remission.
鳞状细胞肺癌 缓解了12年
i was able to walk my daughter down the aisle last may.
去年五月我送女儿走上了红毯
thank you, dr. wilson.
谢谢 Wilson医生
i did the math. 74 children are alive today
我算了一下  74个孩子因为你 活到了今天
mikey kimble started kindergarten before the age cutoff.
Mikey kimble 赶在超龄前去上了幼儿园
he would have graduated high school last year.
他应该去年就高中毕业了
i flunked a year.
我留级了一年
was anybody in this room really a patient of mine?
这里有谁真的是我的病人吗
they're somewhere.
别的地方肯定有的
they're giving you a standing "o" somewhere.
他们在别的地方为你起立鼓掌呢
they exist. you saved their lives.
他们是存在的 是你救了他们的命
actually, more impressive-- they're too busy to be here.
事实上 更了不起的是 他们因为太忙 今天不能赶来
what's this?
这是什么
a glowing letter of recommendation you just wrote for me on my laptop.
你在我电脑上为我写的一封漂亮的推荐信
i notice it's lacking your signature at the bottom.
我发现下面少了你的签名
don't you think you're being a bit premature predicting house's demise?
你不觉得现在就预言House会完蛋 有点操之过急吗
not demise. just implosion.
不是完蛋 只是崩溃
he's going through a rough time, but so far, he's been handling it--
他正在走一条艰难的路 但是到目前为止 他都处理得...
house.
House
your shoes are wet!
你的鞋湿了诶
glad to see your emotional turmoil hasn't dulled your powers of observation.
很高兴看到你的情绪紊乱 并没有影响你的观察力
i know you're responsible.
我知道是你干的
no, you don't. 'cause i didn't do it.
不 你不知道 因为不是我
whatever it is.
不管你说的是啥
but if i had shoved those season tickets down some toilets,
但我要是有把那些票扔进马桶里
i would have done it because you asked me to.
也是因为你让我这么做
you wanted to replace wilson. i prank wilson all the time.
你想取代Wilson  Wilson被我从早整到晚的
enjoy.
好好享受吧
i got you three, but i drank them.
我给你买了三瓶 不过我自己都喝了
you didn't have to call me, but i appreciate i made the list.
你不用打给我的 不过我很高兴自己能上榜
it wasn't entirely unselfish.
并非是毫无私心的
i didn't feel right approaching any of my terminal patients,
我觉得不应该接触任何晚期的病人
but...
可是...
what is it like?
是怎样的?
does it ever stop being surreal?
那种不真实的感觉会消失吗?
it'll stop in about...
到一定时候会消失的...
five or six months, give or take, in your case.
就你来说的话 五六个月之后吧
you know what happened to me today?
你知道我今天遇上什么事了吗?
one of my patients suddenly started crying.
我的一个病人忽然就哭起来了
it can't be your first.
总不是你第一次见了吧
the first one... who was crying for me.
但是第一个...为我哭的
it's the human response.
这是人之常情啊
it's either overly saccharine, because giving sympathy makes them feel better,
这要么是太过虚情假意 因为给予同情能让他们感觉好受一些
or they ignore you,
要么他们是忽视你
because hiding from mortality makes them feel better.
因为躲避死亡能让他们感觉好受一些
why can't they just say something that makes me feel better?
他们怎么就不能说句让我宽心的话呢?
like what, exactly?
能说什么呢?
i don't know. no.
- 我也不知道 - 是吧
you'd be doing what, two weeks on, two weeks off?
你是怎么打算的 两周上化疗 两周休息?
so maybe do your first round, see how it goes.
也许还是应该做一轮试试 看感觉怎么样
maybe not as horrible as you fear.
说不定并不像你害怕的那么难受呢
then do the second round, enjoy your two weeks off,
然后再做第二轮 好好休息两周
and revisit the decision. rinse, repeat.
回头考虑自己的决定 重新洗牌 再次重复
i just can't envision spending my remaining time
我只是无法想象把剩下的时间耗费在
in a chemo suite in princeton.
普林斯顿的化疗病房里
i want to...
我想要...
enjoy myself with family and friends.
和家人与朋友们平静享受剩下的时光
friends or friend?
朋友们还是朋友?
hi, this is greg house. again.
你好 又是Greg House
third message, hopefully indicating how much i want you to call me back.
第三次留言了 希望这能显示出我多么想让你回电话
i'd say that your son is dying to increase the urgency,
我本想说你儿子快挂了应该能提高点优先级
but you probably already know that.
但你大概早就知道了
the fake people who care that wilson stays alive didn't work,
用假人来关心Wilson死活已经不管用了
so i need the real people who care about him to tell him what an idiot he's being.
于是我需要真关心他的人来告诉他 他有多么白痴
where are we going? i just got paged to go to the bathroom.
- 我们这是往哪去啊? - 我刚接到传呼让我去厕所
i don't know where the rest of you are going.
谁知道你们要去哪啊
some of our patient's symptoms might be physiological,
病人有些症状可能是身体上的
and some might be psychological.
而另外一些则可能是精神上的
you think being forced to bury painful memories is making symptoms worse?
你认为被迫将痛苦的记忆压抑起来让他的症状加重了?
grief avoidance can lead to all sorts of anxiety disorders,
对悲伤的一味逃避可能引起各种焦虑失调
which can manifest into physical illness.
并从而发展成外在的病症
let's assume...that all his symptoms are real symptoms.
我们还是假设...他的症状都是真的症状吧
so we're going to avoid grief avoidance?
于是我们要逃避对悲伤的逃避了?
studies after september 11th showed that repression was actually better for coping
911之后有研究显示压抑与终日沉浸于悲伤相比
than dwelling in misery.
反而是更好的应对方式
what about polycythemia vera? rbcs are slightly elevated, but not that much.
- 真性红细胞增多症? - RBC只是略微升高 不足以证明
hodgkin's lymphoma? would have showed up in the pet scan.
- 霍奇森氏淋巴癌? - 在PET扫描中应该能看出来
what if your guy got hurt at practice?
如果病人只是在训练时受伤了呢?
and, like everything else, just didn't tell anyone.
然后他就像平常一样跟谁都没说
could have set off dic, would explain everything.
然后引发了弥漫性凝血 能够解释所有症状
i thought you had to go to the bathroom. i didn't say i had to go in.
- 以为你说要去洗手间呢 - 又没说要进去
need some more mops in here!
再多拿些拖把来!
what exactly are you looking for?
你到底在找什么?
blood. if your spinal fluid is yellow instead of clear,
血 如果你的脊髓液是黄色而不是透明的话
it means you've had a subarachnoid hemorrhage.
说明你有蛛网膜下腔出血
what does your brother say to you?
你弟弟一般都跟你说什么呢?
does he tell you you're gonna be okay?
他会告诉你一切都会没事吗?
doesn't really work like that.
不是那样的
i think you hear your brother's voice for a reason.
我觉得你听到你弟弟说话是有理由的
thought you guys said that i hear things because i'm sick.
- 以为你们说我听见声音是因为我病了呢 - 没错
yes. but that doesn't explain why you don't hear a different voice.
但是这并不能解释你为什么听到的不是别人的声音
i think your mom didn't let you deal with the grief of losing your brother properly.
我认为你妈妈没有给你机会 正确面对失去弟弟的悲伤
there are people here who could help you with that.
我们这里有专人可以为你提供帮助
okay.
好吧
the opening pressure's way too high.
开口压太高了
the prodigal daughter returns.
浪女回头了
you taking me up on my offer to off you?
决定接下我炒你鱿鱼的邀请了?
think i've still got some leftover propofol.
我的异丙酚可还有剩的哟
spoke to wilson.
跟Wilson谈过了
he's angry because i want him to live longer.
因为我想让他多活几天 他就生气了
who wouldn't be? friends respect each other's decisions,
- 真是人之常情哟 - 朋友会尊重彼此的决定
even if they don't agree with them. it's called loyalty.
哪怕有不同意见也是如此 这叫做忠诚
loyalty is a tool to get people to do things they don't wanna do.
忠诚只是用来让人做他们不愿做的事情的工具
but you do want to.
但是你依然想要做个忠诚的人
you may have rationalized it a hundred different ways,
大概你心里已经找了千百个理由
but the fact is, you fired me so that i'd be forced
但是事实 你炒我的鱿鱼是为了迫使我
to spend the rest of my life doing exactly what i wanted to do.
在余生之中能做我想做的事情
it was probably the most...
这可能是...
selfless thing anyone has ever done for me.
别人为我做过最无私的一件事
and you don't even like me that much.
而你还没那么喜欢我呢
i surrender.
我投降啦
i have been a disloyal...
我是个不忠实...
disrespectful jerk.
毫不尊重人的混蛋
i should have listened to what you wanted.
我应该仔细听听你想要什么
i'm still not letting my parents return your call.
我还是不会让我父母回你电话的
i made a reservation for two at carmine's.
我在Carmine's订了两个人的位
tonight. 8:00.
今晚八点
no more tricks. no more manipulations.
不玩花样 不再摆布你
said machiavelli.
马基雅维利本人说的吗? (意大利佛罗伦萨的政冶家外交家)
just...
只是...
two friends enjoying the time they have left.
两个好朋友享受他们剩下的些许时光
please, don't-- i'm not. i promise.
- 求你了 不要再... - 我不会的 我保证
just dinner? that depends on how much you have to drink.
- 只是晚饭 - 当然也取决于我能把你灌到多醉
that sounds nice.
听起来不错啊
mom.
妈妈
i came as soon as i got your message. is he gonna be okay?
我一接到信息就立即赶来了 他没事吧?
we're hoping it's just excess fluid on his brain from an extreme migraine,
我们希望只是由于严重偏头痛引起的脑积液
which isn't good, but it's treatable.
虽然不是好事 但是可以治疗的
he's scheduled to get an mri as soon as these meds start taking effect.
只要这些药起效了 我们立即送他去做MRI
we found that picture in his dorm room.
我们在他房间里找到这张照片的
i'm not sure what derrick's told you, but...
我不知道Derrick是怎么告诉你的 但是...
he's been hearing christopher's voice for the last ten years.
他十年来一直都能听到Christopher的声音
and it's possible that repressing all that grief he's felt
而且他被压抑的悲伤
is actually causing some of derrick's symptoms.
甚至可能是他发病的部分原因
i don't even know if this voice in my head is something i invented
我甚至不知道我头脑中的声音到底是我自己创造出来的
or if it's what christopher was really like.
还是真正Christopher原来的样子
with no photos, no video...
没有照片 没有视频...
my memories...
而我的记忆...
i really don't have any anymore.
我已经很难回忆起来了
maybe you could just...
你能不能...
tell me a little bit about him?
告诉我一点关于他的事情啊?
i'm sorry. it was a long drive in.
抱歉 我开了好长时间的车
i'm gonna go get a coffee.
我得去买杯咖啡了
okay.
好吧
97 years old,
97岁
and you told her she was pregnant.
你告诉她她怀孕了
well, it cured her hiccups.
她的打嗝可是一下子就治好了
i didn't expect her to cry for quite so long.
只不过我没料到她能哭那么长时间
now, i know that the tiramisu is great here,
那个...我虽然知道这里的提拉米苏棒极了
but i actually ordered off-menu.
但我还是忍不住点了菜单上没有的菜
great.
好极了
i told you you didn't hang the bear bag high enough.
我早告诉你那个捕熊袋挂的不够高
it was a smart bear. i'm almost certain he untied my knots.
是那只熊太聪明了好么 我发誓它自己把绳子解开逃跑的
well, he wasn't that smart. he left the oreos behind.
是哦 他也没那么聪明 给咱剩下了好多奥利奥
you hiked for 32 miles eating nothing but creamy filling.
你走了32英里路 只吃里面的奶油夹心
the black stuff is overrated.
巧克力本来就不好吃
to climbing the hill.
敬勇攀高峰
okay.
好
if i did decide to...
如果我真的决定要...
stick around a little longer--
再多活一阵--
don't do that to me, wilson.
别这么对我 Wilson
no, i'm not, i'm just--
不 我不是那个意思 我是说--
i do feel pretty good and i...
我现在感觉还不错啊 而且...
maybe i should try it for a little while.
我觉得我可能还是应该先试试再说的
well, i...
这个么 我...
i think that's reasonable.
我觉得这是个明智的决定
are you c-conning me?
你...你又诓我呢是吧?
you're conning me.
你又在诓我了
just because you folded,
你立场改变了
that means it must be some evil plan?
就说明是中了我的奸计了?
well, that's usually how it works with you.
这不是你的一贯作风吗
you drown me in nostalgia so i'll think about our friendship
你让我深陷于美好的怀旧不能自拔 让我回忆我们的友谊
and feel some kind of loyalty and agree to more chemo!
然后让我从角落里找出点忠诚来 同意继续化疗
that was real nostalgia. it was real emotions, a real decision.
可那些回忆都是真的 情感也是真的 你的决定也是真的
a decision that i just made for you!
可那决定是为了你才做的!
i need you, okay?
我需要你 好不好?
i want you to be around as long as possible.
我想让你尽可能长时间地留在我身边
'cause i don't know what i'm gonna do without you.
因为如果没了你 我真不知道我会做出什么事来
no. no.
不 不
don't do that.
少来这套了
i don't owe you anything.
我不欠你任何东西
our entire relationship has been about you.
我们的整个关系都是关于你的
my dying is about me.
而我死是关于我的
look at you. you don't wanna die.
瞧瞧你吧 你根本不想死啊
of course, i don't wanna die! well, then fight.
- 当然啊 我当然不想死! - 那就咬牙战斗下去啊!
i did! i tried. one time.
- 我战斗了啊! 我试过了! - 就那一次
house, get out of my car.
House 从我车里滚出去
you don't have to just accept this. yes, i do have to accept this.
- 你不用就这么认命的啊 - 我不认命还能怎么办啊!
i have five months to live, and you're making me go through this alone!
我只有五个月可活了 而你却要逼我独自度过这段时光!
i'm pissed because i'm dying, and it's not fair.
我生气是因为我要死了 而这不公平
and i need...
我需要...
i need a friend. i need to know that you're there.
我需要一个朋友 我需要知道你就在我身边
i need--
我需要--
i need you to tell me that my life...
我需要你告诉我 我的生命...
was worthwhile, and i...
是有意义的 而且我...
i need you to tell me that you love me.
我需要你告诉我 你爱我
no.
不
i'm not gonna tell you that unless you fight.
如果你就此放弃不再和癌魔战斗 我永远也不会告诉你的
blood vessels are nonreactive. it's not a migraine.
血管无反应 不是偏头痛
i'm not feeling so great. how much longer?
我不太舒服 还要多久?
finishing up.
快完了
thank you, dr. adams.
谢谢你 Adams医生
it looks like the ceiling might collapse.
看起来天花板像是要塌了
what are you doing back here? we got a case.
- 你来干嘛? - 有新病例了
assume the status is: patient's getting worse.
我猜状况是 病人情况越来越糟
you guys are confused.
你们越来越困惑
you think actually showing up for work
你觉得来上个班
is enough to make up for ruining an mri, endangering the patient,injuring us?
就能让大家原谅你破坏MRI 将病人置于危险之中
this isn't about the damage.
这跟造成多大损害没有关系
you're back because something's going on with wilson. i'm done with wilson.
- 你回来是因为Wilson出了什么问题 - 我再也不管Wilson了
what does that mean, you're done with wilson? if he's not dead, you're not done with wilson.
什么叫做你不管Wilson了? 只要他没死 你的责任就没完
you suddenly think you're gonna make a difference?
你忽然就觉得你能起什么重大作用了?
you can't just abandon him. it's in his hands now.
- 你不能就这样抛弃他 - 一切选择都在他了
get any good pictures before the mri drowned?
MRI泡水之前得到什么图像没有?
enough to know it wasn't a migraine.
足够排除偏头痛
and the patient mistook me for adams.
病人还把我和Adams认错了
come with me.
跟我来
so what do you think's gonna happen when i stick a needle into his eardrum?
你们觉得我把针扎进他的耳鼓会怎么样呢?
you quizzing us? oh, this is a good quiz.
- 你在考我们吗? - 这可是道不错的考题
he'll scream in pain. don't listen to her.
- 他会痛得叫出来的 - 别听她的
very small needle, very steady hand.
小小的针头 稳稳的大手
now, when i pull back on the plunger, what do you think's gonna come out?
现在 如果我把注射器向后拉 会出来什么呢?
air.
空气
boy, that air sure is red.
哎哟 这空气可真红呢
persistent stapedial artery.
镫骨动脉突出
it should disappear in the embryonic stage, but just like his dead brother,
在胎儿期就应该消失的 但这就像他死掉的弟弟一样
he really can't let go.
他总是放不开手
an artery's been pressing against the temporal lobe of his brain, right above the ear canal.
一条动脉压迫着他大脑的前额叶 正在耳道上方
it explains the voices, the dizziness, everything.
可以解释幻听 眩晕 一切症状
now you guys can explain how we're gonna make him better.
现在跟他解释怎么把他病治好
will my brother's voice go away?
我弟弟的声音会消失吗?
you're being an ass.
你是个混蛋
i just cured a patient. how 'bout you?
我刚治好了一个病人 您干吗去了?
you can't just give up on wilson. you know he needs you.
你不能就这么放弃Wilson 你知道他需要你
you know he's making an impossible choice. he just doesn't want to live in pain.
你知道他在做一个不可能的选择 他只是不愿意活在痛苦之中
life is pain! i wake up every morning, i'm in pain.
生活就是痛苦! 我每天早上睁开眼 就一下子被丢进痛苦里面
i go to work in pain. you know how many times i wanted to just give up?
我每天在痛苦中工作 你知道我有多少次想放弃吗?
how many times i thought about ending it?
有多少次想干脆结束这一切吗?
you here to yell at me or give me hockey tickets?
你是来吼我的 还是来给我冰球季票的?
had to delay the surgery because our patient drank ammonia from the janitor's cart.
手术被推迟了 因为病人喝了工友车上的氨水
i guess...
我想...
he didn't want to live without his brother's voice.
他不想再也听不到弟弟的声音吧
where are you going?
你上哪儿去?
you can't wait to die?
等不及想死了是吧?
here, let me help you. hey! house!
- 来 我帮你! - 嘿
house! see? you wanna live! he did something stupid.
House
he's not gonna do it again.
再不会有第二次了!
you're resisting me because it's our human responsibility to stay alive!
你抵抗的原因是我们为人就是要活着的!
you made your point, house! stop!
你已经说明你的观点了 House 快住手!
you've spent your whole life looking for the truth.
你终自己一生寻找真理
but sometimes the truth just sucks.
但有的时候真理就是这么不堪!
i'm, uh...
我...
i'm gonna be leaving, uh, quite a bit earlier than we had talked about.
我大概要...比我们先前讲好的早一些离职
the...next day or two.
可能...就是接下来几天吧
what happened?
怎么了?
something between you and house?
你和House又怎么了?
he's not my child.
他又不是我家孩子
i cannot be responsible for the happiness of gregory house.
Gregory House幸不幸福根本不干我事好吗!
well, uh...i'll get these to frankel.
好吧...我会把这些交给Franknel的
okay. thank you.
好的 谢谢了
you are responsible.
就是关你的事
the past 20 years you've had three wives,
过去的二十年你换了三个老婆
hundreds of colleagues, thousands of patients.
相处过几百个同事 经手过上千个病人
but you've kept that one best friend.
而你最好的朋友一直只有一个
he wants me to suffer a misery
他想让我经受
that i don't want to go through.
我不愿经受的痛苦
chemo won't make your life any better.
化疗是不会让你的生活好起来
but caring will.
但关心人会
enduring pain to do some good for someone you care about...
照顾你所关心的人 为他们忍受痛苦
isn't that what life is?
这不正是生活的意义吗?
mom?
妈妈?
yeah?
怎么?
that picture of christopher that i had on the stand.
我放在桌上那张Christopher的照片
did you take it?
你拿走了吗?
yes. did you throw it out?
- 是的 - 你把它扔掉了吗?
if i agree to get the surgery, can you bring that picture back?
如果我同意做手术 你能把照片还给我吗?
not home. house.
- 不在家 - House
i'm ready to start the next round of chemo.
我准备好继续下一轮的化疗了
why?
为什么?
because you need me
因为你需要我
and...
而且...
i don't think that's a bad thing anymore.
我也不再觉得这是件坏事了
no.
不
you're the only one i listen to.
我只听你的话
the last couple of days, i didn't, and i almost killed my patient.
这几天里我没听你的 结果差点害死了病人
so i think it's time for me to accept that...
于是我觉得嘛 是时候承认...
you're just smarter than i am.
你比我聪明啦
are you really okay
你真的能接受
that there's only five months left?
咱们只有五个月了这个事实吗?
no.
不能
but it's better than nothing.
但总比什么都没有强吧
how do we start?
怎么开始呢?
i'm not gonna say "i love you."
我不会跟你说我爱你的
thank god. you got any oreos?
感谢上帝哟 你还有奥利奥吗?
how are you feeling?
感觉如何?
the surgery worked.
手术成功了
how can you tell?
你怎么知道?
'cause christopher's gone.
Christopher不在了
and this is the peak. almost 8,000 feet.
这就是顶峰了 大概8000英尺高
you do realize that my leg situation has deteriorated a little
你总意识到我的腿比上次咱登山的时候
since the last time we went hiking. just add another day.
- 瘸了那么一点点吧? - 再多加一天呗
this is matt johnson, the hospital lawyer.
这位是Matt Johnson 医院的律师
yes. i have decided not to proceed with the sexual harassment case.
是的 我决定不再追究那起性骚扰案了
are these yours?
这是你的吗?
the plumber retrieved them from the hospital outflow pipe.
水管工从医院阻塞的下水道里找到了这些
they caused a sewage backup that ruined the mri, and they have your name on them.
堵塞的污水毁掉了MRI 而这些东西上有你的名字
gregory danger house.
Gregory "危险" House
it's...a very common name.
这不是...很平常的名字嘛
these apparently have your fingerprints on them also.
而且你的指纹显然也在上面
okay. why don't you tell me how many hours of picking up trash you want me to do.
好吧 你就直说你想让我捡多少小时的垃圾吧
house...i tried to keep this internal.
House...我不想把这件事闹大的
the fire department handed the tickets to the police who contacted your parole officer.
但消防部门把证据交给了警方 而警方给你的保释官打了电话
it's felony vandalism.
这是破坏公物的重罪
he's gonna revoke your parole. there's nothing we can do.
他将撤销你的假释 我们已经无能为力了
you have to report to mercer county jail on monday to serve out the rest of your sentence.
你周一就得回到默瑟郡监狱报道 服完你剩下的刑期
and that's... that's how long?
那是...多久?
i'm sorry. how long?
- 我很抱歉 - 多久啊?
six  months
六个月
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入